A Guide to the Andrew Chapel United Methodist Church Cemetery Burial or Removal Permits, 1933-1942
Virginia Room, Fairfax County Public Library
The Andrew Chapel United Methodist Church Cemetery Burial or Removal Permits, 1933-1942
Fairfax County Public Library
MSS 01-05
0.5 linear feet
The Andrew Chapel United Methodist Church Cemetery Burial or Removal Permits collection consists of 0.5 linear feet and spans the years 1933-1942.
Commonwealth of Virginia - State Department of Health
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None
Acquisition Information
Unknown
Historical and Biographical Information
Andrew Chapel is located on Trap Road at its intersection with Leesburg Pike in Vienna, Fairfax County, Virginia. The church dates to 1854 and has an active congregation today. The church was founded in 1844 after the Methodist Episcopal Church split into two churches (Methodist Episcopal Church and Methodist Episcopal Church, South) due to tensions over the issue of slavery. Andrew Chapel was founded by a portion of the congregation of a chapel on Towlston Road that left to join the Methodist Episcopal Church, South. The chapel was named for Bishop James Andrew (1794-1871), who in 1844, was asked by the church at the ninth General Conference of the Church in to resign his office of bishop because he owned slaves, thereby escalating tensions within the church and prompting the founding of the Methodist Episcopal Church, South.
The Andrew Chapel cemetery has more than 250 burials from the mid-nineteenth century to present day, including many Civil War soldiers and members of the founding families of the church. The cemetery bounds the chapel on two sides and is maintained by a non-profit association.
Established by Virginia Code during the years represented in this collection, burial or removal permits were issued by the local registrar based on a certificate of death filed by the undertaker. Burial or removal permits were then delivered by the undertaker to the sexton or other person in charge of the cemetery or burial ground before interring the remains.
Scope and Content
The Andrew Chapel United Methodist Church Cemetery Burial or Removal Permits collection consists of 0.5 linear feet and spans the years 1933-1942. The collection includes 115 permits, issued either by the Commonwealth of Virginia, State Department of Health for burial in or removal to the Andrew Chapel cemetery or by the District of Columbia for removal of remains to Andrew Chapel cemetery for interment. Subjects covered are burial records and the Andrew Chapel cemetery.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Virginia Room Cemetery Files, Virginia Room, Fairfax County Public Library
None
Index Terms
Andrew Chapel United Methodist Church (Vienna, Va.); Burial records - Virginia - Fairfax County
Container List
- Amelia Adams, 1938 February 3 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Annie Adams, 1937 March 29 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Robert Lee Adams, 1939 May 5 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Thomas Stanhope Adams, 1941 July 10 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- John Howard Allen, 1941 October 25 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Joseph Herbert Allen, 1939 August 16 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Geneva Catherine Barbee, 1937 May 10 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- William Matthew Barron, 1941 September 5 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- George O. Berry, 1939 January 2 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Effie Bonham, 1938 October 17 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Mary Jane Brashears, 1933 May 2 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Clark Burgess, 1935 January 19 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Marguerite Burgess, 1935 January 19 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Stillborn Infant (Woodrow and Louise Carper), 1936 September 23 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Charles Caton, 1936 January 17 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Enoch Francis Caton, 1936 August 1 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Mand. C. Cockrill, 1941 January 23 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Stonewall J. Cockrill, 1940 April 20 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Gunnell Coleman, 1941 September 9 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Virginia Compton, 1940 May 18 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Henry A. Crider, 1937 February 17 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Hugh Charles Cumberland, 1936 January 23 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Thomas Riley Cumberland, 1935 June 6 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Betty Ann Darne, 1938 July 4 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- May Lillian Darne, 1936 February 10 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Octavia Darne, 1934 January 15 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- William Dauster, 1938 November 22 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Katie L. Davenport, 1940 January 29 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Ella G. Davis, 1941 September 26 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Gilbert Beebe Davis, 1937 September 17 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Ira J. Davis, 1940 September 12 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Milton Davis, 1938 November 1 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- John Wm. Day, 1935 December 5 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Ellen Dick, 1942 April 2 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Herbert M. Dyer, 1939 March 31 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Elizabeth M. Eager, 1938 April 10 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Nancy E. Eager, 1938 April 10 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Davenport Blockwell Elgin, 1938 January 25 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- John Fogle, 1936 November 24 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Charles L. Follin, 1936 October 31 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Edgar W. Follin, 1935 April 18 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Fletcher Follin, 1934 December 15 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- James Lee Follin, 1936 August 18 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Jane Elizabeth Follin, 1937 November 19 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- John Nelson Follin [photocopy], 1937 October 5 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Mildred Anne Follin, 1938 July 5 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Sarah Jane Follin, 1933 December 11 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Montgomery Fox [photocopy], 1933 November 27 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Elliot Upton Frenzel, 1937 August 7 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Amy Gheen, 1941 March 11 (Box 1, Folder 50)
- Annie Virginia Gibson, 1941 June 6 (Box 1, Folder 51)
- George Washington Gibson, 1938 August 10 (Box 1, Folder 52)
- Louis Joshua Gibson, 1938 June 28 (Box 1, Folder 53)
- Rose B. Graham, 1935 January 3 (Box 1, Folder 54)
- Annie R. Gunnell, 1939 January 21 (Box 1, Folder 55)
- Wilbert Palmer Heatwole (?), 1936 June 10 (Box 1, Folder 56)
- Emily Jane Huffman, 1933 July 14 (Box 1, Folder 57)
- Louise V. Hughes, 1937 March 5 (Box 1, Folder 58)
- Ralph Hughes, 1936 October 20 (Box 1, Folder 59)
- Ira David Hummer, 1940 July 20 (Box 1, Folder 60)
- Thomas Hummer, 1940 February 23 (Box 1, Folder 61)
- Chas. W. Iden, 1934 July 14 (Box 1, Folder 62)
- Mandley Iden, 1941 September 25 (Box 1, Folder 63)
- Chas. F. Jackson, 1936 February 25 (Box 1, Folder 64)
- Siddie Jackson, 1934 November 1 (Box 1, Folder 65)
- Ida M. Jarrett, 1933 October 12 (Box 1, Folder 66)
- Wilson Jarrett, 1939 June 5 (Box 1, Folder 67)
- Mary Katherine Kidwell, 1935 February 17 (Box 1, Folder 68)
- Leo L. Lee, 1940 December 2 (Box 1, Folder 69)
- Norman C. Lee, 1939 October 8 (Box 1, Folder 70)
- Annie Elizabeth Leigh [photocopy], 1933 December 27 (Box 1, Folder 71)
- Thomas J. Loveless, 1939 January 2 (Box 1, Folder 72)
- James Edward Lyons, 1941 April 21 (Box 1, Folder 73)
- Saloma Zebiah Marshall, 1936 October 8 (Box 1, Folder 74)
- Burdett Hickman Martin, 1936 August 24 (Box 1, Folder 75)
- Rose McDaniel, 1937 July 20 (Box 1, Folder 76)
- Mattie L. Money, 1942 February 10 (Box 1, Folder 77)
- Raymond N. Moore, 1939 September 25 (Box 1, Folder 78)
- Carrie L. Oliver, 1933 December 8 (Box 1, Folder 79)
- Jonas Oliver, 1937 January 21 (Box 1, Folder 80)
- Elizabeth Mabel Payne, 1941 July 11 (Box 1, Folder 81)
- Elwood B. Payne, 1939 May 24 (Box 1, Folder 82)
- Sarah Peacock, 1937 April 30 (Box 1, Folder 83)
- John N. Pearson, 1935 August 5 (Box 1, Folder 84)
- Thomas E. Pearson, 1936 July 28 (Box 1, Folder 85)
- James Pollen, Jr., 1941 October 29 (Box 1, Folder 86)
- Charley Purley, 1936 July 13 (Box 1, Folder 87)
- Josephine Ramey, 1935 February 6 (Box 1, Folder 88)
- Rosalie Redmond, 1935 August 8 (Box 1, Folder 89)
- Lewis F. Rollins, 1937 January 15 (Box 1, Folder 90)
- Mary Shirley, 1938 December 17 (Box 1, Folder 91)
- Virginia Lee Shotroff, 1939 May 6 (Box 1, Folder 92)
- Fannie Skinner, 1941 August 2 (Box 1, Folder 93)
- Willie Withers Skinner, 1942 March 10 (Box 1, Folder 94)
- Grace Mae Slicer, 1938 June 9 (Box 1, Folder 95)
- Hattie Longstreet Smith, 1937 March 16 (Box 1, Folder 96)
- Elizabeth Snow, 1940 November 14 (Box 1, Folder 97)
- Daniel J. Sullivan, 1941 May 5 (Box 1, Folder 98)
- Thomas Tudor Taylor, 1940 July 5 (Box 1, Folder 99)
- James Thompson, 1934 March 15 (Box 1, Folder 100)
- James Owen Thompson, 1940 November 20 (Box 1, Folder 101)
- Wilbert Grant Thompson, 1934 December 28 (Box 1, Folder 102)
- John Alderton Tracy, 1938 July 7 (Box 1, Folder 103)
- Joyce Ann Tracy, 1941 December 27 (Box 1, Folder 104)
- Hugh A. Wiley, 1934 April 14 (Box 1, Folder 105)
- Jesse Hammel Wiley, 1939 October 7 (Box 1, Folder 106)
- Joseph Harold Wiley, 1936 June 28 (Box 1, Folder 107)
- Mary Margaret Wiley, 1933 November 4 (Box 1, Folder 108)
- Virginia Wiley, 1934 November 30 (Box 1, Folder 109)
- Hubert Brook Wine, 1933 December 18 (Box 1, Folder 110)
- Chas. E. Wyncoop, 1935 October 5 (Box 1, Folder 111)
- Walter Wyncoop, 1937 May 24 (Box 1, Folder 112)
- Mary E. Wynkoop, 1935 July 5 (Box 1, Folder 113)
- Minnie Wynkoop, 1939 December 19 (Box 1, Folder 114)
- William F. Young, 1940 May 12 (Box 1, Folder 115)
- List and Photocopies of Burial and Removal Permits, Undated (Box 1, Folder 116)